Guide to the Russ Wiltse Video Collection
Russ Wiltse Video Collection
Oral History of American Music
Russ Wiltse Video Collection
2001 2008
RWA
Oral History of American Music
30 Computer Files
Wiltse, Russell
Scope and Contents
The Russ Wiltse Video Collection consists of 20 interviews with 19 composers. The interviews were conducted by filmmaker Russ Wiltse and others, and used in the making of his 2014 documentary "Beautiful Scary: Contemporary Music in America."
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research. The finding aid includes links to stream most interviews online via Oral History of American Music's (OHAM) A/V access system, Aviary. Yale users can login to Aviary using their Yale University ID, to stream these interviews without restriction. Other users are able to request access to interviews directly through Aviary. For access instructions, and to request transcripts of an interview, see OHAM's website.
Some interviews may be restricted. Access to these restricted interviews may only be granted to a patron who has first obtained direct permission from the interviewee or their estate.
Some interviews may not have been digitized or are otherwise not available to stream online. However, these interviews may have been transcribed. Please see contact OHAM for more details.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by surname of interviewee.
General
This finding aid describes digitized copies of the interview recordings in this collection. Oral History of American Music also holds the original recordings, on a variety of legacy audio and video formats.
Composers 20th Century
- Babbitt, Milton
  - Babbitt, Milton, 2004 February 5; RWA 2 a-b; Swartz, Steven N.; Approximate running time: 81 mins
    Interview Location
    New York, NY
    Babbitt, Milton, 1916-2011
- Carter, Elliott
  - Carter, Elliott, 2004 February 6; RWA 9 a; Swartz, Steven N.
    Carter, Elliott, 1908-2012
- Chen, Yi
  - Chen, Yi, 2001 September 8; RWA 4 a-b; Wiltse, Russell; Approximate running time: 67 minutes
    Moab, UT
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    .mov files
    Chen, Yi, 1953-
- Corigliano, John
  - Corigliano, John, 2003 January 31; RWA 1 a; MacMillan, Kyle
    Denver, CO
    Corigliano, John, 1938-
- Crumb, George
  - Crumb, George, 2004 October 21; RWA 10 a; Bruns, Steven, 1957-
    Colorado Springs, CO
    Crumb, George, 1929-
- Glass, Phillip
  - Glass, Phillip, 2004 November 11; RWA 6 a; MacMillan, Kyle
    Boulder, CO
    Glass, Philip
- Gordon, Michael
  - Gordon, Michael and Julia Wolfe, 2005 July 28; RWA 14 a-b; Wiltse, Russell
    North Adams, MA
    Gordon, Michael, 1956-; Wolfe, Julia (19581218)
- Lang, David
  - Lang, David, 2005 July 20; RWA 11 a; Swartz, Steven N.
    Lang, David (David A.) (1957-01-08-)
- Larsen, Libby
  - Larsen, Libby, 2005 July 20; RWA 15 a-b; Wiltse, Russell
    Aspen, CO
    Larsen, Libby (1950-12-24-)
- Oliveros, Pauline
  - Oliveros, Pauline, 2007 June 29; RWA 16 a-b
    Scope and Contents
    Oliveros, Pauline, 1932-2016
- Reich, Steve
  - Reich, Steve, 2005 July 28; RWA 12 a-c; Wiltse, Russell
    Reich, Steve, 1936-
- Riley, Terry
  - Riley, Terry, 2005 December 29; RWA 13 a-b; Wiltse, Russell
    Richmond, CA
    Riley, Terry, 1935-
- Rorem, Ned
  - Rorem, Ned, 2004 February 5; RWA 7 a-b; Swartz, Steven N.
    Rorem, Ned, 1923-
- Rouse, Christopher
  - Rouse, Christopher, 2003 July 3; RWA 8 a; Wiltse, Jennifer
    Rouse, Christopher, 1949-2019
- Sheng, Bright
  - Sheng, Bright, 2003 July 26; RWA 3 a; Wiltse, Russell
    Santa Fe, NM
    Sheng, Bright, 1955-
- Tan, Dun
  - Tan, Dun, 2007 July 20; RWA 17 a; Wiltse, Russell
    Tan, Dun, 1957-
- Tower, Joan
  - Tower, Joan, 2008 April 14; RWA 19 a; Wiltse, Russell
    Red Hook, NY
    Tower, Joan, 1938-
  - Tower, Joan, 2008 August 30; RWA 19 b; Wiltse, Russell; 1 Videocassette
    Angel Fire, NM
- Wourinen, Charles
  - Wuorinen, Charles, 2008 April 13; RWA 18 a; Wiltse, Russell
    Wuorinen, Charles, 1938-
- Zhou, Long
  - Zhou, Long, 2001 September 8; RWA 5 a-b; Wiltse, Russell
    Zhou, Long, 1953-